Alan Boe 7206 Major Ave. N. Brooklyn Center, MN 55429 Home Phone (763) 549-5558 / Cell (763) 438-4314 Slanboe@gmail.com

## Summary

An Electrical Estimator/Project Manager and Risk Manager with experience in Limited Energy, Outdoor and Commercial/Industrial construction projects. My field of experience is diverse. I have managed many limited energy projects for many multi-dwelling unit developments for customers such as Senior Housing Partners, Sherman and Associates, The Waters Group, Guardian Angels, Crestview, St. Therese, CA Ventures and Volunteers of America The largest project that I worked on was the Sphere in Las Vegas Nevada where I was the network infrastructure project manager. I have also worked on many outdoor electrical projects for owners such as Mn/DOT, various cities, counties, private businesses, churches, school districts and universities.

My strengths include the ability to manage material and labor costs on projects, being able to quickly resolve construction/design issues as they become known while also finding the best cost effective solution for the customer and the general contractor.

## Experience

Archkey Solutions, Plymouth, MN Limited Energy Project Manager

2021-2024

At Archkey I worked as a low voltage project manager for many medical clinics, the City of Burnsville and the Sphere. These projects included AV systems, access control, CCTV, fiber optic cabling, copper network cabling, ordering material, coordinating material shipments and labor needs.

Collins Electrical Construction Company, St. Paul, MN 2012-2020 Limited Energy Project Manager

In this role I was the project manager for many large senior living buildings and communities along with many large multi-dwelling unit buildings. My responsibilities included designing low voltage systems with owners/general contractors/subcontractors, pricing the installation of theses systems, coordinating manpower and material along with coordination with the different building utilities and service providers. These systems include voice, data, CCTV, guest entry, access control, fiber optic and CATV cabling.

Egan Company, Brooklyn Park, MN 2011-2012 Collisys merged with Egan in 2011 Safety Coordinator/New Hire Coordinator Responsibilities included attending OSHA Consultation meetings, jobsite safety audits, maintained commercial driver's license files and different types of safety training for field employees. Hired new field employees for Egan Company, Interclad and FabDuct.

Collisys, New Hope, MN 1998-2011 Safety Director / EEO Officer 2008-2011

Planned, coordinated and conducted safety training for general worksite conditions. Provided site specific training for hazards such as confined space, bucket trucks, forklifts, scissor lift and power actuated tools. Conducted monthly safety committee meetings with the goal to improve company safety. Implemented changes of company issued Personal Protection Equipment which increased how often PPE was used and reduced injuries. Helped injured employees return to work as quickly as possible including finding positions to fit within their required work restrictions. This reduced our Experience Mod Rate and reduced insurance costs. Served as company EEO Officer and ensured that the company was in compliance with city, county and state requirements while also working at job fairs and community outreach programs.

Estimator / Project Manager Outdoor Division 2005-2008

Estimating and project management for various outdoor projects which includes outdoor lighting, traffic signal systems and fiber optic cabling installations for various cities, counties, Mn/DOT, school districts and many private companies.

Estimator / Project Manager Systems Division 2001-2005

Estimated and project management for low voltage projects which included the installation of voice, data, sound system and fiber optic cabling and controlling material costs and labor. Projects included working at universities, churches, Ramsey County, Mn/DOT and many private companies. Management of test equipment such as OTDRs, Power Meters, UTP Meters and ensuring certificates of calibration were up-to-date. Maintained company computers and telephone systems.

Estimator / Project Manager Commercial, Industrial Division 1998-2001 Estimated and project management of indoor electrical projects. Customers included various private companies, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, and cities in Minnesota and Wisconsin.

## Education

Dunwoody Institute, 1998 - Electrical Construction Design and Management Dunwoody Institute, 1993 - Electrical Construction and Maintenance

## Certifications

Mn/DOT Signal & Lighting Certification-Level II / Certified Traffic Control Supervisor BNSF Railroad Safety Trained / Metro Transit LRT Safety Trained U of M Erosion/Sediment Control Specialist OSHA - 30 Hour Construction Safety and Health

Train the Trainer / 16 Hour – Asbestos North Hennepin Technical College 8 hour Rigging Inspection and Signal Person

Affiliations

Chairman of the Electrus Federal Credit Union Supervisory Committee for over 9 years.

References Available upon request